Listen, I don't see myself as someone
who's afraid to fail. However, if I'm
being honest, I do see myself as someone
who's afraid to try, especially when I'm
with other people. If I'm writing a song
alone in my room, there's no problem. I
don't even have an awareness of the sour
notes I'm singing, of the bad ideas I'm
throwing out, because there's no one
there to witness it. So, it's just like,
whatever. Who cares? But sometimes when
I write with friends, I can find myself
being very self-conscious. I was writing
with two friends recently, and we did
five days of writing. And at the end of
it, we didn't have any songs. And they
were very sweet about it. They were
like, "Listen, sometimes you can channel
magic, and sometimes you just don't."
But I was like, "No, there is a problem,
which means there is an answer." And I
was like reviewing the footage in my
mind, and I was like, "Okay, I feel like
this time especially, I felt too
embarrassed, too scared to like throw
out ideas. It's like when I would offer
options, I would find myself like
singing very quietly to myself so that I
could hear if I thought it was a good
idea before I shared it with my friends.
But the truth is that I was singing so
quietly, even I couldn't tell if it was
a good idea or not. I couldn't hear it.
I have this belief about songs, and
maybe all creative things, that the song
already exists. It's like out there in
the ether. And my job as a songwriter is
not to invent something, but just to
open myself wide enough to channel it
through to this realm. And it made me
realize like, yeah, when I'm singing so
small, my channel's not open wide
enough. And if I want to bring a song
in, I need to be brave enough to sing
big. Anyway, here's a song about that.
>> [music]
[music]
>> You could live afraid of failure.
You could make yourself so small.
>> [music]
>> Go
and try to tame her.
But to fly, you got to fall.
You can't know the ending while you're
standing at the start.
>> [music]
>> So, let it happen, babe. Show them who
[music] you are. Sing [singing]
big. Let them hear your song.
Dare to do it wrong. [music]
Let your spirit shine.
Sing out. [singing]
Making yourself small worked, it worked
by now. [music] It's time to let it out.
I'm still learning how to open. [music]
I'm learning how to play.
And I'm not here to do it perfect. No.
I am here to do it brave. [singing]
You can't know the ending while you're
standing at the [music] start.
So, let it happen, babe. Show [music]
them who you are. Sing
big. Let them hear your song.
Dare to do it wrong. Let your [music]
spirit shine. [singing]
Sing out. Making yourself small worked,
it worked by now. It's time to let it
[singing] out.
You don't have to be the very best.
Welcome to your life, it's not a test. I
[music] just want to see you come and
let it out.
Everybody dancing to the beat. If you
got a body, move your feet. I just want
to see you come and let it [singing]
out.
Sing big. Let them hear your song.
Dare to do it wrong. Let your spirit
shine. [singing]
Sing out. If making yourself small
worked, it would have by now. It's time
to let it out.
Anyway,
that's my song. My name's Tessa Violet.
This song is out now, and I am putting
out a new song every month this year.
So, if you would like to be notified
when the next song comes out, there is a
link in the description of this video.
What else? Oh, if you really want to be
a friend, you can support me on Patreon.
I'm doing these super cutesy postcards.
I'll probably print some lyrics on the
back, and then I will autograph it. I
have not done that yet, obviously.
Anyway, yeah. I hope that my song cured
your fear of failure, and you never fear
again, and you have a perfect life. I'm
sending you so much love, and I hope you
have an amazing day.
Mwah.